

SAAD BARADAN

SOFTWARE ENGINEER





https://www.linkedin.com/in/saad-baradan



https://github.com/saadricklamar

SKILLS

Frameworks/Languages

- JavaScript
- NativeScript
- Python
- HTML5/CSS3
- React/Redux
- React Native
- Vue.js
- Node.js/Express
- PostgreSQL/Knex
- Linux
- Heroku
- Travis CI
- Mocha/Chai
- Jest/Enzyme

Systems/Practices

- Git/Github
- Agile Development
- Jira
- Teaching
- Client Management

EDUCATION

Turing School of Software & Design, Front-End Engineering Jan 2019 - Aug 2019

Colorado State University,

M.A. Philosophy

Sept 2013 - May 2015

University of Colorado Denver, B.A. Philosophy

June 2007 - May 2011

SUMMARY

I am a Software Engineer with an emphasis on Front-End Technologies. My passion for programming came out of my passion for philosophy where I learned about the power and utility of logic. I enjoy practicing test driven development, putting together thoughtful and intuitive UIs, and collaborating with teams to enhance our products and user experiences.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Delivery Software Engineer, IQGeo

January 2020 - Present

- Utilize JavaScript, React, Python, and other technologies to build out new features for clients
- Collaborate with clients to create various design documents (LOE, SRS, & LLD)
- Oversee code deployments to various environments (QA, STG, & PROD)
- Build Front-End geo-spatial features for clients using Leaflet, OpenLayers, and ESRI
- Use Linux to develop, test, and deploy software
- Implement new installs of myWorld and other IQGeo products for clients
- Use FogBugz & Jira to track, troubleshoot, and resolve bugs for clients in a timely manner

Client Engagement Specialist, Zillow Group

September 2015 - January 2019

- Use CRM's such as Salesforce and Big Purple Dot to manage and coach Zillow Group clients
- Help agents install, navigate, and troubleshoot mobile applications
- Connect consumers to agents vis-a-vis text, email, and phone

Projects

My Portfolio

https://find-saad.herokuapp.com/

My portfolio website highlighting my projects, photography, and more.

Tech Used: JavaScript, HTML/CSS, React, React Scroll, EmailJS, Jest/Enzyme, Heroku